Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number six and this exercise, we are asked to find the time complexity of this
method.
Both the video and think about this mess.
Remember when you see a raise?
Think about and but not all time and all the times we have sold the exercise number five and we have
seen that a for loop and ordinary for loop, but with a different increment plus plus and that is equal
times due.
It will become log n as complexity.
And not linear, it is logarithmic.
So please pay attention when you see a for loop.
Now, let's solve this exercise.
We start from here, we have this is the body of the method.
And we have here, let me make it different, the color in green.
We have this.
This is.
The body of the fur, the outer loop, so the outer loop.
The outer loop here will be resulting in.
I equal to zero, which is the initial.
And I less than a rate at length, remember every.
Array dot length is the referred as an.
Think about it as an.
OK, so and the increment is a plus plus.
So this array is going through all the elements of a from zero to N, this complexity of this loop is
o of an OK.
So this would result in all of an.
Now inside this hour, this story, this loop, we have another loop nested loop and it the start from
Jay Equal to zero two Jay less than NW and its increment in J Plus Plus.
So it moves it from and goes through all elements from zero to N and is printing.
Is this.
OK.
So.
This complexity of this array is an.
But the complexity of this is all of an.
OK.
And the outer loop is of.
This is oh of an as we have said, that the outer loop, this is that loop and the green is the inner
loop and in blue is sort of in yellow is sort of one.
OK, so we have the outer loop is moving through.
All the elements from zero to N and the inner loop is executing the code from zero to end, and the
code is a system that are to print.
This is often times and times and so one.
This is the inner times, how many time it it is executing time and it is executed and times.
And this loop, the inner loop in green is executed and times because with this nested loop inside a
bigger loop and an outer loop that it is going from zero to end elements.
So one times and bounds and this result in and squares.
So the time complexity of this exercise and this method and this algorithm is of.